Register of the Nym Wales papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE OF NYM WALES AND EDGAR SNOW, 1935-1954 (Box 34)
  - Sun, Madame Yat-sen (Soong Ching Ling, China Defense League), 1939 (Box-folder 34: 21)
  - Walsh, Richard J., 1944 (Box-folder 34: 22)
  - William, Maurice (Sun Yat-Sen Day Project), 1944 (Box-folder 34: 23)
  - Worcester, Elizabeth, 1940 (Box-folder 34: 24)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 34: 25)
- MISCELLANY, undated (Boxes 34-37)
  Contains miscellaneous printed matter and stencils of the guides to the collection prepared by Nym Wales.
  - Greeting cards, calling cards, shopping lists, menus, receipts, and notes (Box-folder 34: 26, 30)
  - Notebooks on the Silesian Loan Question (1735-1756) (Box-folder 34: 27-29)
    Contains three notebooks.
  - Stencils (inked)
    - "Notes on the Beginnings of the Industrial Cooperatives" (Box 35)
    - "Notes on the Chinese Student Movement, 1935-1937" (Box 36)
    - "Notes on the Sian Incident, 1936" (Box 37)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1930-1987; (bulk, 1930-1940) (Boxes 65, 67-72, Box fAJ, Oversize photo file, Slide cabinet)
  Contains photographs, negatives, slides, and albums depicting Nym Wales, Chinese communist leaders, INDUSCO (Chinese Industrial Cooperative) activities, and other events related to the communist movement in China during the 1930s and 1940s. Also includes typewritten notes about the photographs, located in envelope A, copper printing plates, photo postcards, woodcut prints, ink drawings, and a charcoal sketch.
  - A: Typewritten notes concerning the photos in the collection, undated (Box 67)
    Most of the notes are in the form of captions for particular photos; however, they should be used with caution as there are certain inconsistencies.
  - B: 4 photos and 1 photocopy of Helen Foster Snow (Nym Wales), 1930s-1954 (Box 67)
  - C: 4 photos of Ida Pruitt at various INDUSCO (Chinese Industrial Cooperative) centers, late 1930s-early 1940s (Box 67)
  - D: 13 photos of Rewi Alley at various INDUSCO centers, late 1930s-early 1940s (Box 67)
  - E: 1 photo of Edgar Snow and O.J. Todd, Head of Famine Relief in China, and 1 photo of Edgar Snow with the Headquarters Company of the First Front Red Army, 1931-1937 (Box 67)
  - F: 2 photos and 2 copyprints of Chou En-lai (Zhou Enlai), 5 photos of Chu Teh (Zhu De), and 1 photo of Lin Piao (Lin Biao), 1937, undated (Box 67)
  - G: 12 photographs of Mao Tse-tung and others, 1930s (Box 67)
    Others pictured include: Chu Teh, Agnes Smedley, Hsiao Hua, Yeh Chien-ying, Ho Tzu-chien, Po Ku, and Chou En-lai. Also contains the first images taken of Kuomintang and communist cooperation in China.
  - H: 36 portraits of Red Army leaders and others, 1936-1937, undated (Box 67)
    Includes images of Chu Pui-teh, Feng Yu-hsiang (Feng Yuxiang), Wang Chen, Li Ming, H.S. "Newsreel" Wong, Chang Yen-ching (Zhang Yanqing), Hsiao Chin-kuang (Xiao Jinguang or Man Ge), Fang Wen-ping (Fang Wenbing), Li Hsien-chen (Li Xianzhen), Lo Chen-yu (Luo Zhenyu), Wang Liang, Ting Chien-hsiu (Ding Jianxiu), Hsiao K'eh (Xiao Ke), Han Ying (or Xiang Yin), Tso Chuan (Zuo Quan or Zuo Shuren), Chiang Ming (Kim San, real name Chiang Chi-rak), Chang Chao-lin (Zhang Zhaolin), Chang Wen-ping (Zhang Wenbing), Ho Lung (He Long), David Yui (Yu Ch'i-wei), Li Fu Ch'un (Li Fuchun), Hsu Hai-tung (Xu Haidong), Hsu Hsiang-chien (Xu Xiangqian), Ch'en Ming-hsu (Chen Mingshu), H.H. Chen, Chiang Kai-shek, P'eng Teh-huai (Peng Dehuai), Seo Kiu-leung, Fu Chiu Kuei (Fu Jiukuai), Lin Yutang, Jimmy Yen (Yan Yangchu), and Hsu Hai-tung (Xu Haidong).
  - I: Group photographs of Red Army leaders and various other communist groups, 1934-1937, undated (Box 67)
    Includes photographs of Liu Zhi, Xiao Ke, He Long, Lin Piao (Lin Biao), Zhu De, Fang Wenbing, Sun Renjiong, Wang Zhen, Shao Kuei, leaders of the 8th Route Army, delegation from the Nanjing Government, the Chinese Second Soviet Congress held February 3, 1934, the Red Army Youth Group, the Northwest Youth Group, and the Guomindang Delegation.
  - J - mJ VII: Scenes of the Red Army and Chinese Communist areas, 1936-1937 (Boxes 68-69)
    Approximately 188 photographs.
  - K - K I: Student demonstrations, 1935-1936 (Box 69)
    Approximately 187 photographs.
  - L: 11 photos of the student movement, undated (Box 69)
    Includes images of the 29th Route Army at Ching Lungshan (Jinglongshan) with student marchers, Constance Chang, Wang Ju-mei (Huang Hua), H.S. "Newsreel" Wong, Frank Smothers, Liu Tsui (Liu Cui), and Kuo Wei-hung (Guo Weihong).
  - M: Photographs taken by James Bertram of the Sian Incident and the Red Army, circa 1936 (Box 69)
    Includes images of the 8th Route Army and mass meetings. Approximately 57 photographs total.
  - N-S: INDUSCO activities, late 1930s and 1940s (Boxes 69-71)
    Approximately 534 photographs. Also includes 7 postcards located in Envelope Q. Photographs in Envelope S taken by George Hogg.
  - T: 15 photos of INDUSCO activities in the Philippines, early 1940s (Box 71)
  - U: Paintings by "left-wing" painters of Peking, 1930s (Box 71)
    Includes 20 photographs, 4 photo postcards, and 9 printed copies of photographs.
  - V: Art works of Wang Chun-chu (Wang Junchu), early 1930s (Box 71)
    Includes photographs, negatives, and photo postcards of the artist's work.
  - W: 4 photographic prints of charcoal drawings by Wang Chun-chu (Wang Junchu), undated (Box 71)
    Also includes a magazine clipping and a note written by Nym Wales about the drawings.
  - mX: 2 woodcut prints, 1 charcoal sketch, and copies of 25 ink drawings of the Long March by unidentified Chinese artists, 1930s-1940s (Oversize-box 65)
    Includes an inventory of the drawings which were originally presented to Nym Wales in Yenan in 1937.
    Access
    Digital use copies of the ink sketches are available on workstations in the Archives reading room. In addition, the sketches have been published in Chang zheng hua ji by Zhen Huang, a copy of which is available in the Hoover Library: http://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/6722695
  - Y: Chinese writers and artists, undated (Box 71)
    Includes images of Liu Hai-Sou (Liu Haisu), Wang Chun-chu (Wang Junchu or Hu Man), Hsiao Ai-mi, Ting Ling (Ding Ling, originally Jian Bingzhi), and Mei Lan, also known by his stage name as Mei Lan Fong (Mai Laifang). Includes images of Mei Lan dressed as both himself and as his female stage persona.
  - Z: 15 photos of activities involving the Korean Village of Lake Geneva, Wisconsin, and the Central Normal College of Seoul, South Korea, 1937, undated (Box 72)
    Also includes images of Louise Yim Hahn and Soon Kyo Hahn.
  - AA-AE: Chinese scenes and other items, undated (Box 72, Oversize photo file)
    Contains various images taken in China, including Chinese student movement demonstrations in Beijing, INDUSCO activities, and Red Army photographs. Envelope AA also includes Japanese photos of Manchuria and Mongolia, photos of an exhibit of Chinese art in the Philippines, handwritten notes, bookplates, and 4 copper printing plates with etchings of Mao Tse-tung and Chu Teh. Envelope AE includes photographs primarily from Edgar Snow's 1939 trip to Yan'an (Yenan) and surrounding communist areas. Envelope mAB located in oversize photo file. Approximately 214 photographs total.
  - AF: Red Army and Chinese Communist members, undated (Box 72)
    Includes images of the Red Army artillery unit, Beijing student demonstrations, Chou En-lai (Zhou Enlai), Red University Army group, Mao Tse-tung, Ho Tzu-chien (He Zizhen), Rewi Alley, Chu Teh (Zhu De), Chiang Kai-shek, Hsiao K'o (Xiao Ke), Hsu Hai-tung (Xu Haidong), Peng Dehuai, and unidentified persons.
  - AG: 6 photos of Nym Wales, 1985-1986 (Box 72)
    Includes 2 images with An Wei.
  - AH: 1 photo Nym Wales with Fu-shih Wang, 1986 (Box 72)
    Also includes an excerpt from Chapter 22 of My China Years describing how Wales and Wang met.
  - AI: 80th birthday and exhibit, 1987 (Box 72)
    Contains 2 photographs of Nym Wales on her 80th birthday and 2 photographs of the "Helen Snow in China" exhibit held in Xi'an, China.
  - fAJ: 3 albums, 1987 (Box fAJ)
    3 small albums containing images of the "Helen Snow in China" exhibit held in Xi'an, China.
  - Slides, undated (Slide cabinet)
    20 slides depicting the charcoal sketches by Wang Junchu (Wang Chün Ch'u), also known as Meng Tou and Li Zo, listed in the Art series.
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1926-1937 (Box 42)
  - Library bound manuscripts, 1926-1937
    These items were originally transferred to the Hoover Institution Library at the time of acquisition, where they were bound and assigned a number. They are referenced elsewhere in the finding aid under the appropriate subject series.
    - 1. "一九三四年白区工人斗争统计 (Yijiusansi nian baiqu gongren douzheng tongji),", 1934
      English translation: "Statistics Regarding the Worker's Struggle in White Areas"
    - 2. "北平市全体学生示威宣言 (Beipingshi quanti xuesheng shiwei xuanyan),", 1936 December 12
      English translation: "Manifesto of the Beiping Student Demonstrations"
    - 3. "我们的呼吁 (Women de huyu)," 北平市学生救国联合会者 (Beipingshi xuesheng jiuguo lianhehuizhe), 1926
      English translation: "Our Appeal," Beiping Student's Federation for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 4. "上蒋委员长及三中全会书 (Shang Jiang Weiyuan changji sanzhongquanhui shu),", 1937
      English translation: "Document Regarding Chiang Kai-Shek Committee Third Plenum"
    - 5. "什么叫做《秘密外交?》 (Shenme jiaozuo 'Mimi waijiao?')," 天津学生扩大宣传示威团 (Tianjin Xuesheng Kuoda xuanchuan shiwei tuan), undated
      English translation: "What Do You Call 'Secret Diplomacy?,'" Tianjin Student's Society for the Broader Dissemination of Information
    - 6. "留东中国学生救亡会宣言 (Liu Dong Zhongguo xuesheng jiuwang hui xuanyan),", 1936
      English translation: "Manifesto of the Committee of Chinese Students in Tokyo for the Salvation of the Nation"
    - 7. "告平津同学书 (Gao ping jin tongxue shu)," 北平燕京大学学生自治会 (Beiping Yanjing Daxue xuesheng zizhi hui), 1934
      English translation: "Letter to [My] Gaopingjin Classmates," Beiping Yanjing University Student Self-Governance Committee
    - 8. "成立宣言 (Chengli Xuanyan)," 北平各界救国联合会者 (Beiping Ge Jie Jiuguo Lianhehuizhe), undated
      English translation: "Founding Manifesto," Members of the Federation of Beiping People from All Walks of Life for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 9. "中国共产党北方局对西安事变和平解决宣言 (Zhongguo Gongchandang beifangju dui Xi'an shibian heping jiejue xuanyan),", 1936
      English translation: "Manifesto of the Northern Office of the Chinese Communist Party Regarding a Peaceful Settlement to the Xi'an Incident of December 12th, 1936 [the kidnapping of Chiang Kai-Shek]"
    - 10. "《一二，一二》纪念宣传大纲 ('Yi Er, Yi Er' Jinian Xuanchaun Dagang)," 西北各界救国联合会宣传部 (Xibei Gejie Jiuguo Lianhehui Xuanchuanbu), 1936
      English translation: "One Two, One Two: A Statement of Leading Principles," The Propaganda Department of the Northwestern Federation of People from All Walks of Life for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 11. "告各党各派书 (Gao Ge Dang Ge Pai Shu)," 西北各界救国联合会宣传部 (Xibei Gejie Jiuguo Lianhehui Xuanchuanbu), 1936
      English translation: "A Message to Every Party and Every Faction," The Propaganda Department of the Northwestern Federation of People from All Walks of Life for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 12. "中华苏维埃人民共和国中央政府《驻》西北办事处命令 (Zhonghua suweiai rengong heguo zhongyang zhengfu《zhu》Xibei banshichu mingling),", 1936 May 21
      English translation: "Order from the Northwest Office of the Chinese Soviet People's Republic Central Government," signed by Chairman Bo Gu
    - 13. "中华苏维埃人民共和国中央政府《驻》西北办事处布告， 主席博古 (Zhonghua suweiai renmin gongheguo zhongyang zhengfu zhu xibei banshichu bugao, zhuxi Bo Gu),", 1936 July 8
      English translation: "Notice from the Northwest Office of the Chinese Soviet People's Republic Central Government," signed by Chairman Bo Gu
    - 14. "中华苏维埃人民共和国中央政府《驻》西北办事处布告(关于母羊)， 主席博古 (Zhonghua suweiai renmin gongheguo zhongyang zhengfu zhu xibei banshichu bugao, zhuxi Bo Gu),", 1936 January 10
      English translation: "Notice [regarding sheep] from the Northwest Office of the Chinese Soviet People's Republic Central Government," signed by Chairman Bo Gu
    - 15. "中华苏维埃人民共和国中央政府《驻》西北办事处土地部布告, 部长王观澜 (Zhonghua suweiai renmin gongheguo zhongyang zhengfu zhu xibei banshichu tudi bu bugao, buzhang Wang Guanlan),", 1936 January 25
      English translation: "Notice on Land Policy from the Northwest Office Land Department of the Chinese Soviet People's Republic Central Government," signed by Minister Wang Guan Lan
    - 16. "中华苏维埃人民共和国中央政府《驻》西北办事处土地部训令 (Zhonghua suweiai renmin gongheguo zhongyang zhengfu zhu xibei banshichu tudi bu xunling, buzhang Wang Guanlan),", 1936 March 26
      English translation: "Notice on Land Policy from the Northwest Office Land Department of the Chinese Soviet People's Republic Central Government," signed by Minister Wang Guanlan
    - 17. "中华苏维埃共和国临时中央政府《驻》西北办事处布告, 主席博古, 财政部长林伯渠 (Zhonghua suweiai gongheguo linshi zhongyang zhengfu zhu xibei banshichu bugao, zhuxi Bo Gu caicheng buzhang Lin Boqu),", 1935 December 1
      English translation: "Notice from the Northwest Office of the Chinese Soviet Republic Interim Central Government," signed by Chairman Bo Gu and Finance Minister Lin Boqu
    - 18. "红军总司令部命令 (Hongjun zongsilingbu mingling),", 1935 November
      Translated as "Order from Red Army General Headquarters." This is a proclamation issued in the name of Zhu De, Commander -in-Chief of the Chinese Red Army, designed to encourage desertion and defection among the Nationalist army personnel.
    - 19. "从武汉到井崗山, 红军生历史第一页 (Cong Wuhan dao Jinggang Shan, hongjun sheng lishi di yi ye),", undated
      Translated as "From Wuhan to Jinggang Mountain: The First Page in the History of the Growth of the Chinese Red Army." Includes original handwritten manuscript in Chinese, as well as both a handwritten and typescript English translation of the manuscript by Nym Wales. Also includes a hand-drawn map of the route.
    - 20. "红一军团在反攻中所经过的战斗表（自一九三四年十月六日起到一九三五年十月二十一日止） (Hong yi juntuan fangong zhong suo jingguo de zhandou biao)," 中国工农红军第一军团司令部 (Zhongguo gongnong hongjun diyi juntuan silingbu), 1935
      Translated to English as "Battles and Experiences During Long March by the 1st Red Army Corps," Headquarters of the Chinese Red Army, 1st Army Corps. Includes information on the army's activities from October 6, 1934 to October 21, 1935.
    - 21. "过去的我 (Guoqu de wo)," 萧华 (Xiao Hua), circa 1936
      Autobiographical manuscript written by Xiao Hua, translated as "My Past Self."
    - 22. Hand bound booklet of Long March personal narratives, 1934-1935
      Includes "楼山关前后 ("All Around Loushan Pass") by Xue Feng and "Yexingjun de yi mu" ("Scene from a Night March") and "Ni pusa" ("Clay Bodhisattva") by Xiao Peng.
    - 23. "告军警书 (Gao junjing shu)," 复旦大学学生救国会 (Fudan danxue xuesheng jiuguo hui), 1935
      English translation: "Document on the Military and the Police," Committee of Fudan University Students for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 24. "告全国同胞书 (Gao quanguo tongbao shu)," 上海复旦大学学生救国会 (Shanghai Fudan danxue xuesheng jiuguo hui), 1935
      English translation: "A Message to All Fellow Citizens," Committee of Fudan University Students for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 25. "复旦大学扩大宣传团前进曲 (Fudan daxue kuoda xuanchuan tuan qianjin qu)," 复旦大学学生救国会 (Fudan danxue xuesheng jiuguo hui), 1935
      English translation: "Fudan University Rally Song for Disseminating Propaganda," Committee of Fudan University Students for the Salvation of the Nation
    - 26. "师大同学为第二次示威运动宣言 (Shida tongxue we di'er ci shiweiyundong xuanyan)," 国立北平师范大学学生自治会 (Guoli Beiping Shifan Daxue xuesheng zizhi hui), 1935
      English translation: "Declaration for a Second Demonstration of the Students of Beijing Normal University," Beiping Normal University Student Group for Self-Governance
  - Brochure for Cathay Hotel in Shanghai, undated
- ART (Folio case, Box 41)
  Contains charcoal drawings by Chinese artist Wang Junchu (Wang Chün Ch'u) and glass plate negative. See also: Envelope mX in the Photographs series.
  - Charcoal drawings by Wang Junchu, 1929, undated (Folio case)
    Folder A: Two portraits of Chinese man (2 poses) Folder B: Two portraits of Chinese workers, one with basket, one with bag Folder C: Two portraits of Chinese workers, one with shovel, one working with hammer and chisel Folder D: Two portraits of Chinese workers, one with a plow, one hauling a load with a rope Folder E: Two portraits of Chinese workers, one portrait of two laborers, one portrait of a worker fishing Folder F: Two portraits of Chinese workers, one portrait of man with a musket and a dead animal at his feet, one portrait of a man eating with chopsticks from a bowl Folder G: Two nude portraits of Chinese women, 1929-1930 Folder H: Two nude portraits of Chinese women, 1929 Folder I: Three nude portraits of Chinese women (one sheet of paper has a portrait on each side) Folder J: Two nude portraits of Chinese women dated 1929, one with 鈞初炭画 (Junchu tanhua: "Charcoal portrait by Junchu") written on the back Folder K: One drawing of a Chinese worker wielding a sickle and cutting grain
  - Glass plate negative and 2 prints of charcoal sketch frescos of the Red Army by Wang Junchu, 1930s (Box 41)
    May be used under supervision only.
- INCREMENTS, 1931-1992 (Boxes 37-40, 43-64, 66, Tape cabinet)
  Contains additional material not yet fully arranged into appropriate series. Files are organized by date the increment was received.
  - 1982 (Box-folder 37: 7)
    Photocopy of Yenan notes and Helen Foster Snow's letter of introduction from Mao Tse-Tung to Teng Hsiao-P'ing (1937). Also includes copies of drafts from Long Thoughts: Essays and a Chinese translation of "Helen Foster's Trip."
  - 1984 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    Draft of My China Years by Nym Wales with handwritten notes and edits throughout.
  - 1985 (Box-folder 38: 2-3, Box-folder 39: 1)
    Contains photocopies of printed matter (1981-1985), relating mostly to Chinese industrial cooperatives, as well as typescripts of My China Years and "Profiles from China." Also included is a printed copy of My China Years (1984), correspondence, biographical information and articles about Rewi Alley and George Alwyn Hogg, a model constitution template for Chinese industrial cooperative societies, publications and directives from the American Committee for Industrial Cooperatives, photocopies of articles relating to cooperatives in China in the 1980s, and accounts of the history of the term "gung ho" as it relates to industrial cooperatives in China.
  - 1987 (Box-folder 39: 2-3)
    Photocopies of excerpts of "Long Thoughts," as well as photocopies of correspondence, including a letter from Huang Hua relating to conditions in Yenan (October 4, 1944). Also included are photocopies of statements, book reviews, and clippings relating to Nym Wales' writings and an exhibit in Xi'an, China entitled "Helen Snow in China," honoring her 80th birthday and the 50th anniversary of her trip to Yenan. See also: photographs in Envelope AI and albums from fAJ.
  - 1988 (Box-folder 39: 4-5, Box-folder 40: 1)
    Printed copy of Profiles from China: People I Have Known (1985), a Korean translation of Song of Ariran (1984), the Bulletin of the Society of Woman Geographers, June 1, 1983 - May 31, 1984, a hardcover copy of My China Years, and a paperback copy of the Chinese translation.
  - 1989 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    Includes a Korean publication with a review of Song of Arirang [sic], a copy of "NüBing LieZhuan, Di Yi Ji" ("Life Stories of the Heroines, First Collection"), and two copies of the Japanese publication People's Waves, one of which contains an interview with Nym Wales. Also included are a typewritten manuscript by Wales entitled, "Long Thoughts, 1989: Essay Memoirs" and four publications (1985-1989) with chapters on Wales in Chinese and Korean, which are loose in box 43.
  - 1990
    - January (Box-folder 43: 2)
      Typewritten manuscript by Nym Wales entitled, "Soundings: Essay Memoirs and Period Pieces."
    - June (Boxes 44-48, Box-folder 49: 1)
      Typewritten manuscripts, dated from 1969-1990, relating to Chinese politics, society, and American history.
    - July (Box-folder 49: 2-3, Tape cabinet)
      Writings, photocopies of photographs, and material relating to an exhibit on Helen Foster Snow, which opened in Beijing on July 10, 1987. Also included is a videocassette entitled, "HFS Exhibition from Photo Album Sent to Her from An Wei."
      - "HFS Exhibition from Photo Album Sent to Her from An Wei," videocassette (Tape cabinet)
        Use copy available. Use reference id 58002_0001_r2017.
  - 1991 (Box-folder 49: 4-5)
    Writings, correspondence, and clippings relating to the life of Helen Foster Snow, Chinese politics and society, and American history (1989-1991).
  - 1992
    - May (Boxes 50-53)
      Writings, correspondence, notes, speeches, articles, news dispatches, books, and clippings relating to various aspects of Helen Foster Snow's life, such as her return to China in 1972, as well as the histories of China, England, and New England (1932-1992). Box 51 contains a Chinese translation of Inside Red China, a Chinese translation of Red Star Over China, a Korean translation of Song of Ariran, and a Japanese translation of My China Years. Box 53 also contains The Saybrook Story: A Dramatized History of Saybrook on the Connecticut River, Founded in 1635, a Japanese translation of My China Years, and several works in Chinese, including: Return to China, Collected Research of Zhang Wentian, and a history of modern China by Zhang Wentian.
    - December (Boxes 54-61)
      Essays, short stories, notes, poems, and correspondence (1980-1992) relating to various aspects of Helen Foster Snow's life, Chinese society and politics, and early American history. Includes biographical information and photocopies of photographs. Box 58 also includes a Dictionary of International Biography. Box 59 includes the works Notes on the Early History of Madison, Connecticut, Volume I; The Photograph (an English translation of selected works of Bing Xin); and The Photograph Collection of Ba Jin which is in Chinese with English translations.
  - 1997, 2011 (Boxes 62-64, 66)
    Includes writings, short stories, correspondence, and unpublished manuscripts, primarily focused on the experience of foreigners in China, the history of New England, and the achievements of Helen Foster Snow. Box 63 includes an envelope with six photos from the inauguration of the Helen Foster Snow School in China, as well as a videocassette of a broadcast on "Song of Arirang" from KBS Seoul, Korea (March 28, 1993). Box 64 includes a book in Chinese entitled Mao Zedong's Homeland by Helen Foster Snow, an unpublished manuscript titled "Scenes from the China Years," and a hardbound copy of a photo essay compiled on the occasion of Wales' funeral, Bridging: A Photo Essay on the Life of Helen Foster Snow (in English with Chinese translations on each page). Box 66 includes handbills, broadsides, posters, dispatches, and news clippings, primarily relating to the Chinese Student Movement from 1931-1937. Also contains posters and pamphlets promoting the cause of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, writings by Nym Wales, and clippings from Chinese newspapers of translated articles by Nym Wales and Edgar Snow.
    - "Song of Arirang" from KBS Seoul, Korea, videocassette, 1993 March 28 (Tape cabinet)
      Use copy available. Use reference id 58002_0002_r2017.